Jingkang Zhang

zjk7773@gmail.com • +1 (510) 345-7475 • San Jose, CA 95117

github.com/JingkangZhang • linkedin.com/in/jingkang-zhang/ • jingkangzhang.com

Summary Statement

Hands-on fullstack Software Engineer with experiences in Web Applications and Saas Platforms. Consistent in delivering key business products and making technical contributions. Strong in problem solving and communication.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Python, CSS, SQL, NoSQL

Frameworks: React, Redux, Redux Saga, Koa.js, Django

Tools: Git, GitHub, GitLab

Work Experience

Rippling June 2022–Present

Software Engineer 2 San Francisco, CA

• Rippling is an all-in-one **HR, IT, and Finance platform**. Work as a full-stack developer on **Performance Management** team, work on Pulse Survey App, Review Cycles App, and Goals/OKR App.

- Build Review Cycles App from scratch, work closely with Designer, UX Researcher, Product Manager, and Customers to gather requirements, discuss product features, go through the initial design, and work with other engineers to design architecture.
- Work on both FE and BE for Review Cycles App: integration with Rippling main app, review cycles configuration and launch, self/peer/upward/downward review stages, calibration stage, and compensation adjustment. Notable contributions: "expander" data middleware, review auto generation, admin APIs, calibration worksheets, main app integration, etc
- Work on FE and BE for Goals App: collapsible hierarchical table: rendering, search, and filtering. Tree-structured OKR progress visualization for different types of Goals: numeric, binary, percentage, etc.
- Technology: React, TypeScript, Python, Django, MongoDB, Git.

TikTok Inc.

May 2021–June 2022

Software Engineer

Mountain View, CA

- Fullstack developer on **CRM system**, an internal platform where operators view and manage TikTok content creators. Used daily by TikTok operations employees to perform their essential job functions and meet their work objectives. 1500+ DAU.
- Deliver key business projects, including a revamped TikTok Creator Verification Process, Creator Onboarding Journey, and various other features on the CRM platform. Work both on the FE and BE.
- Work on high priority compliance projects. Communicate extensively with Legal and complete projects under tight timelines.
- Perform oncall rotations, code reviews, technical reviews, and product reviews. Conduct interviews (about 3/week), co-mentor new joiners, onboard new members, onboard new oncall engineers.
- Technology: React, Redux Saga, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Node.js, Koa.js, SQL, MongoDB, Git.

Amazon June 2020–October 2020

Software Development Engineer Intern

Newark, NJ

- Fullstack SDE intern on Audible Financial Systems team. Created an internal event management console.
- Technology: React, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Java, Node.js, DynamoDB, Git.

ByteDance May 2019–August 2019

Frontend Engineer Intern

Beijing, China

- Frontend SWE intern on Toutiao team. CRM platform and user dashboard. Web-crawling and data-scraping.
- Technology: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS/HTML, Node.js, Git.

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science, Minor in English

Jun. 2018 - May 2021